Guide to the Theological Discussion Group Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Theological Discussion Group Papers, Series I
  - Slonimsky, Henry (1884- )
    - The Religious Foundations for Enduring Peace, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Smith, Dwight C.
    - Man As A Sinner, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35A)
  - Smith, John Edwin (1921- )
    - Christianity and Philosophy: The Problem of a Christian Philosophy, 1959 Nov (Box 3, Folder 35A)
  - Spiegelberg, Frederic (1897- )
    - Mysticism in Hindu Tradition (Box 3, Folder 35A)
  - Steere, Douglas Van (1901- )
    - A Chapter in Ecumenical Encounter, 1961 Nov (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Evangelism and Christian Fellowship, 1938 Feb (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - The Holy Spirit (God and Man), 1939 Feb (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Protestant Piety Today, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - The Role of the Mystical Experience in Religion and Morality, 1935 Nov (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Supplement to the Christian Approach to the World Religions, 1959 Mar (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - The Christian Approach to the World Religions (This was reprinted from the Friends Journal of Aug 4, 1956), 1959 Mar (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Stinnette, Charles R. (1914- )
    - Theology and Pastoral Care, 1956 Nov (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Tavard, George (1922- )
    - Melchior Cano, or the Waning of an Idea, 1961 Nov 4 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Thomas, George Finger (1899- ), 1936 Feb
    - Can We Believe in Progress? (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Christian Ethics and Moral philosophy, 1951 Nov (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Christian Ethics and Political Realism, 1958 Mar (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Creation and Redemption, 1949 Nov (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Love and Justice: Perfection vs. Compromise, 1942 Mar (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Reinhold Niebuhr's Doctrine of Man as Creature, Image of God, and Sinner, 1949 Nov (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Some Christian Affirmations, 1943 May 7-9 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Thomson, Everett Clay
    - The Providence of God, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Tillich, Paul (1886-1965)
    - The Bible and Systematic Theology, 1947 Mar (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Contemporary Protestant Theology and the Bible, 1955 Mar (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Eschatology and Personal Destiny, 1940 Nov (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - The Holy Spirit and the General Concept of Spirit, 1939 Feb (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - The Idea of the Personal God, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - The Marxist View of History
    - The Present World Situation and the 1942 Nov 39A Christian Message (First and Second Drafts), 1936 Feb 4 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Redemption in Cosmic and Social History, 1944 Nov (Box 4, Folder 39A)
    - Religion and the Visual Arts, 1955 Nov (Box 4, Folder 39A)
    - What Strategy Should the Church Adopt with Reference to Communism?, 1937 Nov (Box 4, Folder 39A)
    - (The following Tillich papers and reprints were not written in con junction with a Theological Discussion Group)
    - The Christian Churches and the Emerging Social Order in Europe, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - The Courage to Be (Terry Lectures), 1950 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Ecumenical Perspectives: Protestant, 1963 May (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Four Bases of Hope for Peace, 1965 Dec (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Psychiatry and Theology, 1956 Oct (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Trueblood, D. Elton Christianity as Idea and as Event (1905- ) (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Ungersma, A. John (1905- )
    - Human Freedom, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Is Protestantism a Positive Principle, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Van Dusen, Henry P. (1897- )
    - The Christian Faith and War, 1943 Oct (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - The Dilemma of the Modern World, 1943 May (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - The Functions of the Church: An Empirical Approach, 1936 Nov (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - The Issues of Christian Unity, 1945 Nov (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - The Limits of Compromise and Asceticism, 1934 Oct (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - The Moral Authority of Jesus, 1941 Nov (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Nature, Grace, Incarnation, 1940 Mar (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - The Problems of Work and Vocation In the Modern World, 1952 Mar (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - The Trinity in Recent Thought, 1961 Mar (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - The War as Seen from the Point of View of Christian Faith, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Vlastos, Gregory
    - A Brief Analysis of Human Nature, 1935 Feb (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Wedel, Theodore Otto (1892- )
    - American Corruptions of Christianity - of the Meaning of the Church, 1954 Mar (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Liturgy and Art, 1956 Mar (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Some Anglican Views on the Church, 1946 Mar (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Widgery, Alban G.(1887- )
    - Metaphysical and Religious Contrasts Between Christianity and Communism, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Wieman, Henry N. (1884- )
    - Our Christian Faith, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Wilder, Amos Niven (1895- )
    - The Basis of Christian Ethics in the New Testament, 1958 Mar (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - The Modern Crisis as Reflected in Contemporary Poetry, 1950 Mar (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Myth and Symbol in the New Testament Supplement: The Cognitive Element in Religious Symbol, 1954 Nov (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - The New Testament Kerygma and the Ethical Teachings of Jesus, 1951 Nov (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Patterns of Belief in Modern Literature, 1950 Mar (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Reconciliation: New Testament Scholarship and Confessional Differences (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - The Status and Content of Biblical Theology (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - The Structure of Poetry-Religious Expression (The following was written for the Thirteenth Symposium of the Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion), 1955 Nov (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Myth and Symbol in the New Testament, 1954 Nov (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Williams, Daniel D.
    - Theology, Philosophy and Truth, 1948 May (Box 5, Folder 46A)
  - Wright, G. Ernest (1909- )
    - Cult and History in the Old Testament, 1958 Oct (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - The Unity of the Bible, 1954 Nov (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Zabriskie, A.C. (1898-1956)
    - The Bible, the Church, and Tradition, 1947 Mar (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Nature, Grace and the Sacraments, 1940 Mar (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Some American Corruptions of the Christian Hope, 1954 Mar (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Anonymous
    - Authority of Scripture: The Liberal Protestant View, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 47A)
    - Buddhism: Nirvana and the World, 1959 Mar (Box 5, Folder 47A)
    - A Christian Interpretation of War, 1943 Oct (Box 5, Folder 47A)
    - The Church as World Community, 1936 Nov (Box 5, Folder 47A)
    - Contemporary Protestant Theology and the Bible (Box 5, Folder 47A)
    - Jesus in the Mass - A Non-Theological Interpretation, 1934 Apr (Box 5, Folder 47A)
    - Mysticism of Bernard of Clairvaux (1090-1153), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 47A)
    - Relevance of Eschatology to the Modern Scene, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 47A)
    - Religious Presuppositions of Ethics, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 47A)
- Other Materials (arranged by organization/type of material), 1933-1958; Series II
  - Theological Discussion Group (East Coast)/Membership lists, correspondence, memoranda, minutes, 1933-1965, no date (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Pacific Coast Theological Discussion Group/Membership list, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - American Theological Society/Membership lists, correspondence, memoranda, 1937-1950 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Chicago Ecumenical Discussion Group/ Memoranda, brochure, 1954, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - The Ethical Reality and Function of the Church, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Preaching as an Expression of the Ethical Reality of the Church, 1942 Nov 13-15 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Comments on "The Responsibility of the Church for the International Order" (Memorandum No. 1 E/40) (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion in Their Relation to the Democratic Way of Life/Memoranda, 1939,1943,n.d. (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - World Council of Churches Study Dept./Paper on Christian Faith and. Psychotherapy, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Virginia Corwin Brautigam/Notes taken at meetings, letter, 1933-1961 (Box 5, Folder 53-54)
  - History/Chronology of the TDG, 1934-1949 by Heather A. Warren, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 55)